<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "../../../lib/docbook/docbook4/docbookx.dtd">
<!--<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC '-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN'
        'http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd'>-->
<article lang="en">
  <articleinfo>
    <title>Solutions of improved Oracle availability and scalability</title>
    <pubdate>2009-09-24</pubdate>
    <copyright>
      <year>2009</year>
      <holder>Elephant Talk Communications, Inc.</holder>
    </copyright>
    <authorgroup>
      <author>
        <personname>Cauchy Song</personname>
        <email>cauchy.song@elephanttalk.com</email>
      </author>
    </authorgroup>
    <revhistory>
      <revision>
        <revnumber>1.1</revnumber>
        <date>2009-9-24</date>
        <authorinitials>Cauchy Song</authorinitials>
        <revremark>Struct adjustment according to discussion</revremark>
      </revision>
      <revision>
        <revnumber>1.0</revnumber>
        <date>2009-9-18</date>
        <authorinitials>Cauchy Song</authorinitials>
        <revremark>First revision</revremark>
      </revision>
    </revhistory>
  </articleinfo>
  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>
      For provide improved Oracle availability and scalability, we have the following solutions,
      Traditional Active/Standby Failover (<emphasis>ASF</emphasis>
      <indexterm><primary>ASF</primary><secondary>Active/Standby Failover</secondary></indexterm>),
      Multiple-Source Replication (<emphasis>MSR</emphasis>
      <indexterm><primary>MSR</primary><secondary>Multiple-Source Replication</secondary></indexterm>),
      <emphasis>Data Guard</emphasis><indexterm><primary>Data Guard</primary></indexterm>,
      and Real Application Clusters (<emphasis>RAC</emphasis>
      <indexterm><primary>RAC</primary><secondary>Real Application Clusters</secondary></indexterm>).
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Active/Standby Failover (ASF)</title>
    <section>
      <title>Active standby pair</title>
      <para>
        In traditional, we use the share storage(SAN or NAS) to store datafiles.
        In the mean time, the Oracle instance on primary machine is up, the
        Oracle instance on secondary machine is down. The HA software automatic
        startup the Oracle instance on secondary machine and takeover the
        service when it found the Oracle instance on primary machine is out of
        service.
      </para>
      <figure>
        <title>Active/Standby Failover</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata width="80%" align="center" fileref="figures/asf.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Comments</title>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Cost</para>
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Requires 2 machines, 2 additional NIC with private network</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>1 oracle licenses</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>SAN</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Advantage</para>
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Cheaper (for already have SAN)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>setup and configure is simple</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>no potential data conflicts or loss</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Disadvantage</para>
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>No any scalability</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>waste one machine</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Switchover is slowly</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Multiple-Source Replication (MSR)</title>
    <para>
      Oracle has two replication solution, ‘Advanced Replication’, or
      ‘Streams Replication’. For symmetry replication, they called
      ‘Multiple-Master Replication (MMR)’
      <indexterm><primary>MMR</primary><secondary>Multiple-Master Replication</secondary></indexterm>
      or ‘Multiple-Source Replication (MSR)’<indexterm><primary>MSR</primary></indexterm>.
    </para>
    <para>
      Oracle said, ‘Advanced Replication’ was obsolete, ‘Streams Replication’
      have many advantage.  Oracle Streams captures and distributes database updates,
      events, and application messages. It can automatically apply updates to destination
      databases; provide an extremely flexible solution for replication. It can support
      both data changes (DML
      <indexterm>
        <primary>DML</primary><secondary>data manipulation language</secondary>
      </indexterm>
      ) and structure changes (DDL
      <indexterm>
        <primary>DDL</primary><secondary>data definition language</secondary>
      </indexterm>
      ).
    </para>
    <section>
      <title>Prerequisites</title>
      <itemizedlist mark="opencircle">
        <listitem>
          <para>Any database producing changes that will be captured must be running
                    in <emphasis>ARCHIVELOG</emphasis> mode.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Set the following initialization parameters to the values indicated
                    at each database in the Oracle Streams environment:</para>
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para><emphasis>GLOBAL_NAMES</emphasis>: This parameter must be set to <emphasis>TRUE</emphasis>.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para><emphasis>COMPATIBLE</emphasis>: This parameter must be set to <emphasis>10.2.0</emphasis> or higher.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Ensure that the <emphasis>PROCESSES</emphasis> and <emphasis>SESSIONS</emphasis> initialization
                parameters are set <emphasis>high enough</emphasis> for all of the Oracle Streams clients.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para><emphasis>STREAMS_POOL_SIZE</emphasis>: This parameter specifies the size of the Oracle Streams pool.
                The Oracle Streams pool stores messages in a buffered queue and is used for internal communications
                during parallel capture and apply. When the <emphasis>MEMORY_TARGET</emphasis>,
                <emphasis>MEMORY_MAX_TARGET</emphasis>, or <emphasis>SGA_TARGET</emphasis> initialization parameter
                is set to a <emphasis>nonzero</emphasis> value, the Oracle Streams pool size is managed
                <emphasis>automatically</emphasis>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Using Oracle Streams for Replication</title>
      <para>The following figure is copy from Oracle N-Way replication example.</para>
      <figure>
        <title>Oracle N-Way replication</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata width="96%" align="center" fileref="figures/msr.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Configuring a Replication Environment</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>For 2-way replication, we require <emphasis>24</emphasis> (Create Queues and Database
            Links, and Configuring 2-Way Replication) steps!</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>We must setup every replicate table for Conflict Resolution!</para>
          <note><title>Conflict Resolution</title>
          <para>When Oracle Streams is used to support replication, both the source and
            destination databases are fully available to end-users for
            <emphasis>reading and writing</emphasis>
            during any replication activity. Because users can update different copies of
            the same table anywhere, it is possible resulting in an update conflict. Oracle
            provides built-in conflict resolution routines, such as
            “<emphasis>latest timestamp</emphasis>” or “<emphasis>overwrite</emphasis>”,
            to automatically resolve potential conflicts. Users can choose
            different resolution methods for different tables. Users also haven the option
            to create their own routines to employ resolution rules tailored to their
            particular business needs. Any unresolved conflicts are logged in the database
            for special handing or re-execution after the conflict is resolved manually.
          </para></note>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Replication Performance</title>
      <para>Oracle Database 11g contains numerous Streams performance improvements.
        Oracle report Oracle Database 11g can replicate <emphasis>over 20,000</emphasis>
        row changes per second with <emphasis>sub-second latency</emphasis> on
        common simple workloads and using common hardware, with <emphasis>over 7 MB/s</emphasis>
        netword bandwidth utilization.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Comments</title>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Cost</para>
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Requires 2 machines</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>2 oracle licenses</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Advantage</para>
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Oracle Streams Multiple-Source Replication can gain a great
                        performance, improved availability and scalability.</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Disadvantage</para>
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Configure is very complex</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Maybe potential require manual interfere or maintain</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Real Application Clusters (RAC)</title>
    <para>Oracle RAC allows multiple computers to run Oracle RDBMS software simultaneously
            while accessing a single database, thus providing a clustered database.</para>
    <section>
      <title>Oracle Database with Oracle RAC Architecture</title>
      <para>The following figure is copy from Oracle RAC example.</para>
      <figure>
        <title>Oracle RAC</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata width="80%" align="center" fileref="figures/rac.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Benefits</title>
      <para>Since Oracle RAC allows multiple computers (instances) to access a single
                database simultaneously, it addresses several areas of database management.
                These areas include:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Fault tolerance (24/7 availability)—Provide continuous uptime
                    for database applications</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>On-demand scalability—Expand capacity by simply adding servers
                    to your cluster</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Flexibility and connection load balancing —Virtualized single
                    instance databases with Oracle RAC One Node</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Lower computing costs—Use low-cost commodity hardware and reduce
                    cost of downtime</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>World-record performance—Runs faster than the fastest mainframe</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Comments</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Cost</para>
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Requires 2 machines, 2 additional NIC with private network</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>3 oracle licenses</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>SAN</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Advantage</para>
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Oracle RAC much stable than MSR</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Switchover is fast</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>no potential data conflicts</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Disadvantage</para>
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Very expensive</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Require a good cluster hardware environment</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Setup is complex</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Oracle Data Guard</title>
    <para>Oracle Data Guard ensures high availability, data protection, and disaster
      recovery<indexterm><primary>Disaster recovery</primary></indexterm> for
      enterprise data. Data Guard provides a comprehensive set of services
      that create, maintain, manage, and monitor one or more standby databases to enable
      production Oracle databases to survive disasters and data corruptions. Data Guard
      maintains these standby databases as copies of the production database. Then, if
      the production database becomes unavailable because of a planned or an unplanned
      outage, Data Guard can switch any standby database to the production role, minimizing
      the downtime associated with the outage. Data Guard can be used with traditional
      backup, restoration, and cluster techniques to provide a high level of data
      protection and data availability.</para>

    <para>With Data Guard, administrators can optionally improve production database
      performance by offloading resource-intensive backup and reporting operations
      to standby systems.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Data Guard Configurations</title>
      <para>A Data Guard configuration consists of one production database and
        one or more standby databases. The databases in a Data Guard configuration
        are connected by Oracle Net and may be dispersed geographically.
      </para>

      <section>
        <title>Primary Database</title>
        <para>A Data Guard configuration contains <emphasis>one</emphasis> production database, also referred
          to as the <emphasis>primary database</emphasis><indexterm><primary>Primary database</primary></indexterm>,
          that functions in the primary role. This is the
          database that is accessed by most of your applications.
        </para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Standby Databases</title>
        <para>A <emphasis>standby database</emphasis>
          <indexterm><primary>Physical standby database</primary></indexterm>
          <indexterm><primary>Logical standby database</primary></indexterm>
          <indexterm><primary>Snapshot standby database</primary></indexterm>
          is a transactionally consistent copy of the primary database.
          Using a backup copy of the primary database, you can create up to <emphasis>thirty</emphasis> standby
          databases and incorporate them in a Data Guard configuration. Once created, Data
          Guard automatically maintains each standby database by transmitting redo data from
          the primary database and then applying the redo to the standby database.
        </para>
        <para>The types of standby databases are as follows:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis>Physical standby</emphasis>
              <indexterm><primary>Physical standby database</primary></indexterm> database</para>

            <para>Provides a physically identical copy of the primary database, with on disk
              database structures that are identical to the primary database on a
              <emphasis>block-for-block</emphasis> basis. The database schemas, including indexes, are the same.
              A physical standby database is kept synchronized with the primary database,
              through <emphasis>Redo Apply</emphasis>, which recovers the redo data received from the primary
              database and applies the redo to the physical standby database.</para>

            <para>As of Oracle Database <emphasis>11g</emphasis> release 1 (11.1),
              a physical standby database
              can receive and apply redo while it is open for <emphasis>read-only</emphasis>
              access. A physical standby database can therefore be used concurrently for
              <emphasis>data protection and reporting</emphasis>.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis>Logical standby</emphasis>
              <indexterm><primary>Logical standby database</primary></indexterm> database</para>

              <para>Contains the same logical information as the production database,
              although the physical organization and structure of the data can be different.
              The logical standby database is kept synchronized with the primary database
              through <emphasis>SQL Apply</emphasis>, which transforms the data in the redo received from the
              primary database into SQL statements and then executes the SQL statements
              on the standby database.</para>

              <para>A logical standby database can be used for other business purposes
                in addition to disaster recovery requirements. This allows users to access
                a logical standby database for <emphasis>queries and reporting</emphasis> purposes at any time.
                Also, using a logical standby database, you can upgrade Oracle Database
                software and patch sets with almost no downtime. Thus, a logical standby
                database can be used concurrently for data protection, reporting, and
                database upgrades</para>

          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis>Snapshot standby</emphasis>
              <indexterm><primary>Snapshot standby database</primary></indexterm> database</para>

            <para>A snapshot standby database is a fully updatable standby database.</para>

            <para>Like a physical or logical standby database, a snapshot standby database
              receives and archives redo data from a primary database. Unlike a physical
              or logical standby database, a snapshot standby database does not apply
              the redo data that it receives. The redo data received by a snapshot standby
              database is <emphasis>not applied until the snapshot standby is converted back
              into a physical standby database</emphasis>, after first <emphasis>discarding
              any local updates</emphasis> made to the snapshot standby database.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Typical Data Guard Configuration</title>
      <para>The following figure is copy from Oracle data guard example.</para>
      <figure>
        <title>Oracle Data Guard</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center" fileref="figures/dataguard.gif"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Data Guard Protection Modes</title>
      <para>In some situations, a business cannot afford to lose data regardless
        of the circumstances. In other situations, the availability of the database
        may be more important than any potential data loss in the unlikely event
        of a multiple failure. Finally, some applications require maximum database
        performance at all times, and can therefore tolerate a small amount of data
        loss if any component should fail. The following descriptions summarize
        the three distinct modes of data protection.</para>

       <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para>Maximum availability</para>
          <indexterm><primary>Maximum availability</primary></indexterm>
          <para>This protection mode provides the <emphasis>highest level of data
          protection</emphasis> that is possible without compromising the availability
          of a primary database. Transactions do not commit until all redo data needed
          to recover those transactions has been written to the online redo log and
          to the standby redo log on at least one synchronized standby database.
          If the primary database cannot write its redo stream to at least one
          <emphasis>synchronized</emphasis> standby database, it operates as if
          it were in maximum performance mode to preserve primary database
          availability until it is again able to write its redo stream to a
          synchronized standby database.</para>

          <para>This protection mode ensures <emphasis>zero data loss</emphasis> except
          in the case of certain double faults, such as failure of a primary database
          after failure of the standby database.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem><para>Maximum performance</para>
          <indexterm><primary>Maximum performance</primary></indexterm>
          <para>This is the default protection mode. It provides the highest level of
            data protection that is possible without affecting the performance of a
            primary database. This is accomplished by allowing transactions to commit
            as soon as all redo data generated by those transactions has been written
            to the online log. Redo data is also written to one or more standby databases,
            but this is done <emphasis>asynchronously</emphasis> with respect to
            transaction commitment, so primary database performance is unaffected by
            delays in writing redo data to the standby database(s).</para>

          <para>This protection mode offers slightly less data protection than maximum
            availability mode and has minimal impact on primary database performance.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem><para>Maximum protection</para>
          <indexterm><primary>Maximum protection</primary></indexterm>
          <para>This protection mode ensures that <emphasis>no data loss</emphasis> will
            occur if the primary database fails. To provide this level of protection,
            the redo data needed to recover a transaction must be written to both the
            online redo log and to the standby redo log on at least one
            <emphasis>synchronized</emphasis> standby database before the transaction
            commits. To ensure that data loss cannot occur, the primary database will
            <emphasis>shut down</emphasis>, rather than continue processing transactions,
            if it cannot write its redo stream to at least one synchronized standby database.</para>
        </listitem>
       </itemizedlist>

      <para>All three protection modes require that specific redo transport options
        be used to send redo data to at least one standby database.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Comments</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Cost</para>
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Requires 2 machines</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>2.25 oracle licenses</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Advantage</para>
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Oracle Data Guard can gain a great performance, data protection, improved availability and scalability.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>no potential data conflicts</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Disadvantage</para>
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Configure is complex</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Sstandby databases only can be read access</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>MSR vs Data Guard</title>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Availability and scalability</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>(Data Guard) Logical standby database can only for queries and reporting purposes.</para>
          <para>In Multiple-Source Replication (MSR)<indexterm><primary>MSR</primary></indexterm>
            Environment, all databases can be read and write.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Network sensitivity</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>(Data Guard) Someone report, if the network have <emphasis>jitter</emphasis>,
            the primary database (work on <emphasis>maximum availability</emphasis> mode
            <indexterm><primary>Maximum availability</primary></indexterm>
            or <emphasis>maximum performance</emphasis> mode
            <indexterm><primary>Maximum performance</primary></indexterm>) can not
            talk to the standby database for a while, users will <emphasis>NOT</emphasis>
            access the primary database for 30 seconds (Maybe down to 15 seconds for good tuning).</para>

          <warning><para>If the primary database work on <emphasis>maximum protection</emphasis> mode,
            <indexterm><primary>Maximum protection</primary></indexterm>
            it will <emphasis>shut down</emphasis> when it cannot write its redo stream
            to at least one synchronized standby database.</para></warning>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Automatic</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>(Data Guard) The standby databases are synchronized with the primary
            database, without manual intervention by the DBA.</para>
          <para>Replication maybe potential require manual interfere or maintain.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Performance</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Replication capture row changes, data guard capture redo data,
            so data guard is fast.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Data integrity</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Data Guard can ensure no data loss, a standby database is a
            transactionally consistent copy of the primary database.</para>
          <para>In Replication, no transactionally guaranty.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Automatic role transitions</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>When <emphasis>fast-start failover</emphasis> (FSF)
            <indexterm><primary>FSF</primary><secondary>Fast-start failover</secondary></indexterm> is enabled,
            the Data Guard broker automatically fails over to a synchronized
            standby site in the event of a disaster at the primary site, requiring
            <emphasis>no</emphasis> intervention by the DBA. In addition,
            applications are automatically notified of the role transition.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Configuration and maintenance</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Configuring and maintenance a Data Guard Environment is easy
                    than replication.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Conclusion</title>

    <section>
      <title>Why not ASF?</title>
      <para>As we said, Active/Standby Failover (<emphasis>ASF</emphasis>)
        <indexterm><primary>ASF</primary></indexterm> require share storage,
        waste one machine, no any scalability, and switchover is slowly.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Why not RAC?</title>
      <para>Real Application Clusters (<emphasis>RAC</emphasis>)
        <indexterm><primary>RAC</primary></indexterm> can be more
        suitable for large concurrent users. Currently, our concurrent user
        for database not great than 30, and will not great than 100 for a long term.</para>

      <para>So most features of RAC no valuable for us except fault tolerance.
        Since RAC very expensive, and require share storage, we should avoid use it.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Our decision</title>
      <para>It's clear to use Multiple-Source Replication (<emphasis>MSR</emphasis>)
        <indexterm><primary>MSR</primary></indexterm>
        for improved Oracle availability and scalability
        for us from the discourses at above. For disaster recovery, we use
        Oracle <emphasis>Data Guard</emphasis>.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Oracle deployment</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata width="96%" align="center" fileref="figures/deploy.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Propose of deployment</title>

    <section>
      <title>deployment architecture</title>
      <para>The following figure is our system deployment architecture. In Madrid,
        we deploy a high availability and scalability system; In Barcelona,
        we deploy a backup system for disaster recovery.</para>
      <figure>
        <title>deployment architecture</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata width="100%" align="center" fileref="figures/deployment.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Switchover to replication database</title>
      <para>If our primary Oracle database out of service, DRE can use the replication
        database automatically, no performance degrade.</para>
      <para>For the switchover, we can use
        <ulink url="http://linux-ha.org/"><citetitle>Linux HA</citetitle></ulink>
        or hard coding in the DRE.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Switchover to physical standby database of Data Guard</title>
      <para>We have very very small chance for both primary and replication database failure.
        In this case, if our DRE and IN can working yet, we should switchover to
        the standby database of Data Guard manually. </para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Propose of procurement</title>

    <section>
      <title>Why not standard edition?</title>
      <para>The price of <emphasis>standard edition</emphasis>
        <indexterm><primary>Standard edition</primary></indexterm>
        is <emphasis>36%</emphasis> of <emphasis>enterprise edition</emphasis>
        <indexterm><primary>Enterprise edition</primary></indexterm>, why not
        standard edition? Because some import features which we should have but
        standard edition missing:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem><para>Oracle <emphasis>diagnostic</emphasis> pack</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem><para>Oracle <emphasis>tuning</emphasis> pack</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem><para><emphasis>Asynchronous change data capture</emphasis></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem><para>Oracle <emphasis>Streams Replication</emphasis>,
          <emphasis>Advanced Replication</emphasis>
          <indexterm><primary>Multiple-Source Replication</primary><secondary>Multiple-Master Replication</secondary></indexterm>
          </para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem><para>Active <emphasis>Data Guard</emphasis>
          <indexterm><primary>Data Guard</primary></indexterm></para>

          <para>Enhances <emphasis>disaster protection</emphasis> investments
            by offloading resource intensive operations to a single <emphasis>physical
            standby</emphasis> database, enhancing overall quality of service.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem><para>In-Memory Database Cache</para>
          <para>Increases responsiveness and throughput by caching frequently
            used data in memory. The In-Memory Database Cache option of Oracle
            Database Enterprise Edition is based on Oracle Times-Ten In-Memory Database.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem><para>Partitioning</para>
          <indexterm><primary>Partitioning</primary></indexterm>
          <para>Enables large tables and indexes to be split into smaller, more
            manageable components, without requiring changes to underlying applications</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem><para>Real Application Testing</para>
          <indexterm><primary>RAT</primary><secondary>Real Application Testing</secondary></indexterm>
          <para>Reduces risk and costs of adopting new technologies, whether it's
            operating systems, servers, or software.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem><para>Materialized View Query Rewrite</para>
          <indexterm><primary>MV</primary><secondary>Materialized View</secondary></indexterm>
          <para>Automatically recognizing materialized view usage to satisfy requests.</para>
          <note><para>Materialized View can be used for fast query or simple replication.</para></note>
        </listitem>

      </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Processor License vs. Named User License</title>
      <para>If our machine have 2 CPU, each CPU have 4 cores, from
        <ulink url="http://www.oracle.com/corporate/pricing/technology-price-list.pdf">
        <citetitle>Oracle Technology Global Price List (July 1, 2009)</citetitle></ulink>, and
        <ulink url="http://www.oracle.com/corporate/contracts/library/processor-core-factor-table.pdf">
        <citetitle>Oracle Processor Core Factor Table (March 16, 2009)</citetitle>
        </ulink>, we known the processor license be equal to 200 Named User License.
      </para>

      <para>Since our concurrent user will not great than 100 for a long term, I
        think we should use Named User License.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Oracle version</title>
      <section>
        <title>32bit or 64bit</title>
        <para>Database is RAM sensitive application, we should pay attention to
          RAM more than CPU.
        </para>

        <para>If our machine RAM great than 4G, we should use 64bit Oracle and
          64bit Operate System.
        </para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>10g or 11g</title>
        <para>Oracle said, 11g have many improvement and enhancement, new users should use 11g.</para>
        <para>You know the adage: "<emphasis>If it ain't broke, don't fix it</emphasis>". After we
          setup the database, I think we should not change the major version, so I suggest use 11g
          for a long term good support and maintenance.
        </para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <index/>
</article>